<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anachronistic Monk</title>
    <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anachronistic Monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>STR: A Disciplined Programmer</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/disciplined-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/disciplined-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>A trainee undergoing military training can disassemble and assemble a machine gun within a minute. At first, this might seem very complex, but everyone in the academy manages to do it. The more pertinent question is not &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo; but &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s because their lives depend on it. Similarly, a disciplined programmer learns the vocabulary and syntax of a programming language with utmost sincerity. Every word in the programming language is sacred, and any non-conformance is akin to blasphemy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 00 Estate: What Happens When the Government Dictates How to Write Code?</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-00-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-00-estate/</guid>
      <description>In the House of Commons of Great Britain, Edmund Burke once stated, &amp;ldquo;There were Three Estates in Parliament; but, in the Reporters’ Gallery yonder, there sat a Fourth Estate more important than them all.&amp;rdquo; As the 21st century dawned, we observed media houses displaying biases towards their respective lobbies. The &amp;rsquo;truth,&amp;rsquo; which should be absolute, now has shades of well-crafted absolution. &amp;ldquo;Whose truth is the truth?&amp;rdquo; is a question I often ask myself while reading news articles on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Wall</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-glass-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-glass-wall/</guid>
      <description>An extraordinary year comes to an end, just like many others, yet I distinctly remember that one year when a remarkable entourage of human beings gathered around me. I had hoped our story would have a happy ending, but sometimes wishes don&amp;rsquo;t come true. Now, staring at the glass wall, I see only myself, alone, burdened with a heavy bag of despair and endless remorse. The seeds I had sown were now bearing their bitter fruit.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
