<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anachronistic Monk</title>
    <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anachronistic Monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>STR: A Disciplined Programmer</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/disciplined-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/disciplined-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>A trainee undergoing military training can disassemble and assemble a machine gun within a minute. It might seem very complex at first but everyone in the academy is able to do it. The more pertinent question is not how but why? Why because his / her life depends on it. The disciplined programmer is a programmer who learns the vocabulary and the syntax around the programming language with utmost sincerity. Every word of the programming language it is a holy word and a non-conformance is bordering blasphemy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 00 Estate : What if government tells you how to write the code?</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-00-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-00-estate/</guid>
      <description>In the House of Commons of Great Britain, Edmund Burke said - &amp;ldquo;There were Three Estates in Parliament; but, in the Reporters’ Gallery yonder, there sat a Fourth Estate more important far than they all&amp;rdquo;. In the advent of the 21 century we have seen media houses exert biases towards their respective lobbys. &amp;lsquo;Truth&amp;rsquo; that is supposed to be absolute has now shades of well crafted absolution. &amp;lsquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s truth is the truth&amp;rsquo; is question that I seldom ask myself while reading news articles over the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Wall</title>
      <link>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-glass-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://durwasa-chakraborty.github.io/posts/the-glass-wall/</guid>
      <description>A fantastic year comes to an end like many others but I still remember the one year in which an entourage of extraordinary human beings had gathered around me. I just hoped that our story might have a good ending but sometimes wishes don’t come true. Staring at the Glass Wall I see myself standing right there alone and carrying a whole bag of despair and endless remorse but then I had sown the seeds and now I witness the repercussions .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
