<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature on Anachronistic Monk</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on Anachronistic Monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 10:56:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Echoes of a Timeless Curse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/echoes-of-a-timeless-curse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 10:56:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/echoes-of-a-timeless-curse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface:&lt;/strong&gt;
Rishi Durvasa, known for his irascible nature, was infamous for his ability to curse. As mythology suggests, Durvasa visited Kanav Rishi&amp;rsquo;s ashram, and Shakuntala was lost in her daydreams of Dushyant. Furious, Durvasa cursed Shakuntala, saying that the one she dreamed of would forget her when the time came. This is a modern retelling of that ancient story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ceiling fans at Kanav Café whirred lazily above, barely stirring the humid afternoon air. Durvasa sat at his usual corner table, nursing a black coffee, his eyes flicking between the window and his notebook. His mind, however, was far from the café, lost in the endless research spiral. He was close—tantalizingly close—to finding a cure for a rare form of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s that had haunted him for years. The disease crept like a thief, stealing memories and identities, stripping people of their past. But Durvasa, with his relentless mind, was determined to stop it. Or, perhaps, rewrite it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Circle of Incompleteness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-circle-of-incompleteness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 01:02:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-circle-of-incompleteness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Am I too comfortable or am I dying from within&lt;br&gt;
I wish at the word go I could drop my skin&lt;br&gt;
The quotes of the dead do not interest me&lt;br&gt;
Nor does the aphorism of the sickened living&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still searching for lost letters and their meaning&lt;br&gt;
To go back to the gardens of my uninterrupted musing&lt;br&gt;
And every night I hope to find the old you;&lt;br&gt;
And every day I hope for a new story to begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
